getsongbpm.com 2019-05-17

# Privacy Policy - GetSongBPM

As the operators of this website, we take your privacy very seriously. We keep your personal information confidential in accordance with all applicable legal provisions and this privacy policy. 

### 1\. Who is responsible for handling your personal information?

The company that defines how your personal data is used is responsible for how such information is handled. 

The personal information collected on our sites and mobile applications is processed by a company governed under German law, Websun Solutions UG, Erich-Weinert-Str. 29, 10439 Berlin, Germany. 

Hereinafter referred to as "THE SITE OWNER" or "We." 

### 2\. Security and Confidentiality 

In order to protect your information, all of your personal data is encrypted in accordance with Transport Layer Security (TLS) standards. TLS is a secure and tested standard that is used in online banking, for example. You can recognize secure TLS connections by the "s" following the "http" in the URL displayed in your browser (https://), or from a padlock symbol displayed next to the URL. 

The personal data we collect is stored only in a secure environment in Switzerland and is treated confidentially. 

However, data transmitted over the internet (e-mail communications, for example) may have security vulnerabilities. Seamless data protection against third party access is not possible. 

### 3\. What are your rights regarding the use of your personal information?

In accordance with regulations for protecting your personal information, you can with draw your consent and exercise your rights to access, rectify, delete, oppose, limit or transfer your data at any time by using our contact form. Data entered in your member area can be deleted or modified at any time, by using your member area settings. 

If you choose to contact us via mail or e-mail, you must include your first and last name, your e-mail and physical address and the reason for your request and/or which of your rights you intend to exercise. 

This request to exercise your rights must include a photocopy of an identifying document bearing your signature, so that we may verify your identity and the address to which we will send our response. We will issue our response within 1 month of receiving your initial request. 

You also have the right to file a complaint with the National Commission for Computers and Liberties (CNIL) on its website at: www.cnil.fr. 

### 4\. Why do we collect your personal information?

We may collect your personal information for the following purposes: 

  * **User/Client Relationship Management for Free and Paid Services:** user registration, potential purchases; invoicing; accounting; loyalty program; client/member relationship monitoring; claims and after-sales service management, rights request management; rectification and opposition, managing unpaid bills and litigation; 
  * **Site Security and Fighting Fraud and Illicit Content** : We collect certain navigation data so that we can ensure our services are secure and detect, avoid or trace any malicious or intrusive access, as well as any violations of our Terms of Service and applicable laws. 
  * **Surveying and Advertising Operations:** loyalty,surveys, product testing, promotions and solicitation actions, organizing contests, lotteries and other promotional operations, developing commercial statistics, creating targeted advertising; for more information about our cookie and plug-in policy, please see Article 12. 
  * **Getting to Know Clients and Site Performance Statistics** : We may use data to help us get to know our members and clients, as well as for statistical purposes, allowing us to analyze site activity and improve the services we offer. For example, we measure our audience through counting site visits and page views, analyzing visitor activity while using the site and measuring how frequently clients and members use our site. 

### 5\. What personal information is collected?

We collect your IP address, as well as information about the browser you used during your visits to our sites. 

When you register for our services, we collect your first and last name, sex, date of birth, city and country of residence, e-mail address, password, links to your social media profiles and personal online pages, favorite music styles (including favorite artists and/or songs), your instruments and information about your mobile phone on a strictly voluntary basis. Required and optional information is denoted by the presence of an asterisk or lack thereof. 

We collect your login data and browsing data when you post content and interact with our services by commenting and adding friends. This data helps us ensure that our site is performing in accordance with our expectations (bug reports, etc.), and it also helps us better understand your musical preferences, enabling us to suggest content and services that are better adapted to your interests. 

We may use cookies, plug-ins and other tracking methods to collect data in accordance with Article 32-II of the amended Law of January 6, 1978 (see Article 12, regarding cookies and tracking methods). 

When you make payments on our sites, your payment is secure. THE SITE OWNER does not collect your payment details; only a payment identifier is collected. Your bank details are only collected by the Stores (Google and Apple), as well as payment providers (including PayPal and Stripe), should you choose to use them. This guarantees the security and confidentiality of your payments and exchanged data. 

### 6\. What kinds of communication might you receive from us?

  * **Follow-Up E-Mails After Registration or Making a Purchase:** These service messages are necessary for the proper execution of the services you have requested. 
  * **Newsletters About Our Activities** : After creating your account, unless you decline this offer, you may receive information and promotions from the SITE OWNER via electronic means of communication (e-mails, SMS, etc.). 
  * **"Partner" Newsletters** : If you have agreed to receive offers from our partners. 
  * **Responses to a Contact Form Request:** The information you indicated on the form, as well as your contact information and IP address, will be retained by us so that we may handle your request and any additional questions which may arise. 

### 7\. How long will my information be processed, and what is the legal basis for how it is handled?

The regulations governing how your personal information is handled will depend on how your personal data is being used. 

The legal framework justifying our handling of your information is as follows: 

  * **The Contract You've Entered by Subscribing to Our Services (TOS):** yourpersonal information will be processed as necessary for the performance of the contract to which you have agreed. 
  * **Consent:** you may expressly consent (via clicking a button, a checkbox, etc.) to having your personal information processed. Some information and content exchanged between users or published on the internet (instant messengers, forums, classes, blogs, etc.) may contain personal information which could impact your private life, the lives of others and third parties. By voluntarily and publicly disseminating such information and content, the user expresses consent for their online disclosures. 
  * **Legitimate Interest** (commercial surveys, fraud prevention, system security…): THE SITE OWNER has a legitimate interest in handling your data when it is justified, fair and does not negatively impact your private life. 
  * **The Law:** processing your personal data becomes compulsory due to a legal obligation or a duty stemming from public interest. 

### 8\. Retention Periods

In principle, personal information pertaining to our members cannot be stored beyond the duration of their registration. 

However, data establishing proof of a right or a contract, as well as data which must be kept in compliance with a legal obligation, may be subject to an intermediate archiving policy for a period not exceeding the duration necessary for the purposes for which the data is being kept, in accordance with applicable laws and provisions. 

Most data (for example, your user account information and your publication history) will be kept for as long as you are a registered member and will be archived for a maximum of 10 years, unless otherwise specified below, after your last activity (for example, your purchases, your logins, etc.). 

Your data may be archived with limited access for an additional period for limited reasons, as [authorized by law](https://www.service-public.fr/professionnels-entreprises/vosdroits/F10029) (payments, taxes, accounting, litigation, etc.). 

Specific Purposes | Duration  
---|---  
User information used for market research purposes | three years after the end of the commercial relationship  
Personal information pertaining to a non-member |  three years after it is collected by the party responsible for handling it or after the last contact is had   
In cases wherein the right to access and rectify identifying information has been exercised  | One year  
In cases wherein the right to oppose has been exercised | Three years  
Targeted advertising/advertisement profiling | 13 months  
Storing credit card data following a payment | 15 months: your bank details are kept by a secure payment provider  
Data which can identify authors of content hosted by our services |  One year (legal basis: [Decree 2011-2019 of February 25, 2011](https://www.legifrance.gouv.fr/affichTexte.do?cidTexte=JORFTEXT000023646013&dateTexte=20180614))   
  
### 9\. Who receives your information?

We treat your data confidentially and securely. Employees have access to this information only if it is necessary for the performance of their duties. 

However, in certain cases we may communicate them to our subcontractors or to third parties: 

#### 9.1 Transmission of Information to Our Contractors

Collected data may be transmitted to one of the subcontractors used by the SITE OWNER for the purposes mentioned above, such as: site hosting, management, operations, processing and application purchase payments. 

#### 9.2 Sharing Information with Third Parties

We may share some of your anonymous or non-anonymous data with partners, such as cookies, plug-ins or technical identifiers. Please see Article 12 hereinafter for more information. 

### 10\. Transmission of Information Outside the European Union

In principle, we do not transmit your data outside the European Union. 

However, in the context of the use of cookies, tracers, plug-ins and technical identifiers, your personal information may be transmitted to companies located in countries outside the European Union for the purposes mentioned hereinafter in Article 12. Nevertheless, there is still a high level of data protection. 

### 11\. What about personal information pertaining to minors?

Our services are not specifically aimed at minors, and as a result, we do not process information that specifically concerns minors. For example, we do not have a specific marketing profile for underage audiences. It is up to parents and persons holding parental authority to decide whether their minor child over the age of 13 is authorized to use our services. 

### 12\. Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

"Cookies" are small files that record information about you on your computer when you visit our websites. 

Different types of cookies are used on our sites and applications, and they have different purposes. Some cookies require your consent, whereas when it comes to other cookies, you can oppose them once they've collected information about you, However, please note that this opposition could change the quality of our services. 

#### 12.1 Cookies That Are Strictly Necessary for the Functioning of Our Services and Transaction Security

These cookies are necessary for the operation of our sites and our applications. They allow you to use our main features (such as shopping cart usage and account access). Without these cookies, you will not be able to use some of our services. 

Name | Cookie Provider | Function  
---|---|---  
*_USER |  | client identifier  
PHPSESSID |  | session identifier  
__cfduid | cloudflare |  identifies individual clients behind a shared IP address and applies separate security settings per client. It does not correspond to any user ID and does not store any personally identifiable information.   
  
#### 12.2 Audience Measurement Cookies

These cookies allow us to better understand the use and performance of our sites and applications and to improve their operation (for example, the most frequently viewed pages, Internet user searches...). 

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service from Google Inc. The IP address provided to Google Analytics by your web browser will not be aggregated with other Google data. The IP addresses are made anonymous, so as to make identification impossible (IP Masking). You can find more information about data protection in conjunction with Google Analytics in Google Analytics Help. 

On our sites, the sending of data to third parties through these cookies is done anonymously and does not identify you, thanks to the IP-Masking function. 

If, by way of exception, cookies collect personal information for third parties, we will implement these cookies only with your express consent and you will have the option to delete them. 

Name | Cookie Provider | Function  
---|---|---  
_ga, _gid | Google Analytics | used to distinguish users  
_gat | Google Analytics |  used to limit data collection on high-traffic sites. It expires after 10 minutes.   
  
#### 12.3 Cookies Used for Advertisement Targeting

We use tracking technologies, including cookies, to adapt advertising to your needs and interests on our sites and those of our partners. 

On our sites, the sending of data to third parties through these cookies is done anonymously and does not identify you, thanks to the IP-Masking function. 

If, by way of exception, cookies collect personal information for third parties, we will implement these cookies only with your express consent and you will have the option to delete them. 

Advertisement rvider Identity | Function  
---|---  
See ads.txt | Personalized display of banner ads  
  
#### 12.4 Cookies from Social Networking and Video Sharing Sites (YouTube)

Social plug-ins add content sharing capabilities to social networks and platforms. These cookies allow an internet user's browsing to be traced, whether they are users of these platforms or not. It is for this reason that user consent must be obtained prior to these cookies being used. 

As a web page provider, we have no knowledge of the content or exact data transmitted, nor how this information is used by various social networks. 

On our sites, the sending of data to third parties through these cookies is done anonymously and does not identify you, thanks to the IP-Masking function. 

If, by way of exception, cookies collect personal information for third parties, we will implement these cookies only with your express consent and you will have the option to delete them 

Name | Cookie Provider | Function  
---|---|---  
__atuvc | AddThis |  A social sharing widget that allows visitors to share content with a range of sharing and networking platforms. It stores a number of updated page shares.   
__atuvs | AddThis | Used to manage the number of shares, until the share cache is updated.  
  
#### 12.5 How to Manage Your Cookies

We invite you to consult the privacy policies of various social networking and sharing platforms in order to obtain precise knowledge about the information they collect and which may be transmitted in connection with their sites and applications, as well as their purposes for collecting your information, particularly with regard to advertising. 

You may change your data access and confidentiality preferences directly within these social networks. 

  * **Facebook:** <http://facebook.com/policy.php>.
  * **Twitter:** <http://twitter.com/privacy>.
  * **Google +1:** <https://developers.google.com/+/web/buttons-policy>.
  * **Pinterest:** <https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy>.
  * **YouTube:** <https://policies.google.com/privacy>.
  * **Disqus:** <https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy>.

First, you can manage your cookies by visiting the cookie manager on the following websites: 

  * <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/>

You can also set your internet browser to disable these cookies. Your browser can also be set to notify you of the cookies that are stored on your computer and ask you whether you'd like to accept them. You can accept or refuse cookies on a case-by-case basis or refuse them systematically, once and for all. These setting are likely to modify your access to the services on our sites which require the use of cookies. 

Here's how to control or prevent the registration of cookies: 

Each browser is configured differently. You can find more information in the help menu for your browser, allowing you to change your cookie preferences. You can disable cookies using the following instructions: 

  1. **if you use Internet Explorer:** In Internet Explorer, click the Tools button, then Internet Options. Under the General tab, under Navigation History, click on Settings. Click the button that says Show Files. Click the Name column header to sort all the files in alphabetical order, then browse through the list until you see files beginning with the prefix "Cookie" (all cookies have this prefix and usually contain the name of the website that created the cookie). Select the cookie(s) with the name "GSBPM" and delete them. Close the window that contains the list of files and click OK twice to return to Internet Explorer. 
  2. **if you use Firefox:** Access the "Tools" tab and select the "Options" menu. In the window that appears, choose "Privacy" and click on "Show Cookies". Locate the files that contain the name "GSBPM". Select them and delete them. 
  3. **if you use Safari:** In your browser, navigate to the Edit menu and choose Preferences. Click on Security. Click on Show Cookies. Select cookies that contain the name "GSBPM" and click Clear or Clear All. After deleting the cookies, click Done. 
  4. **if you use Google Chrome:** Click the icon opening the Tools menu. Select Options. Click the Advanced Options tab and navigate to the "Confidentiality" section. Click the Show Cookies button. Locate the files that contain the name "GSBPM." Select them and delete them. Click "Close" to return to your browser. 

### 13\. Information Collected by Our Mobile Applications

If you use our mobile apps, some personal data may be collected by the publishers of the operating systems used in your mobile phone (iOS, Android, Windows, etc.). 

We invite you to read the privacy policies of these operating system vendors to learn how your data is used and potentially change your operating system settings regarding geolocation, notifications, microphone access, advertising trackers and other audience measurement services. If you refuse certain options, certain services may no longer work. 

#### 13.1 Authorizations Required by Our Android Mobile Applications

The list of special permissions required by each of our Apps is displayed during its installation. 

Name | Function | Type  
---|---|---  
ACCESS_NETWORK_STATE | Allows applications to access network information | Standard  
ACCESS_NETWORK_STATE | Allows applications to access network information | Standard  
INTERNET | Allows internet access | Standard  
BILLING | Allows you to make in-app purchases | Special  
RECORD_AUDIO | Allows an application to record audio | Special  
SYSTEM_ALERT_WINDOW | Allows an application to create windows, displayed on top of all other apps | Special  
WAKE_LOCK | Prevents the processor from going to sleep or hiding the screen | Special  
  
For a list of special permissions granted to an installed App, tap "Settings," then "Apps," and select the name of the App for which you want to view permissions. Granted permissions are displayed under "Permissions". 

To enable/disable an authorization, press "Permissions" and change the settings.
